Armin once told me
that beyond the wall
lies a great expanse of water.
He called it the sea.
And I always wondered...
what's beyond that?
♪ Like the sky at night ♪
*ATTACK ON TITAN*
Season 03  Episode 01
♪ There in the dark ♪
♪ You can hide your fear ♪
♪ Can lie my dear ♪
♪♪
♪ What's the lie? ♪
♪ What's the truth? ♪
♪ What to believe? ♪
♪ Like a fallen angel ♪
♪♪
♪ Into the starry night ♪
♪ Fly to heaven ♪
Episode Title: "Smoke Signal"
Hey, Sasha, you even
try to steal any more food,
and we'll have
Captain Levi chop you into
bite-sized pieces. Got it?
Who, me?
I would never! Probably.
Hey! Did you guys
wipe the mud off your shoes
before you came in?
Huh?
Are you kidding me?
Do you not see all this
stuff we're carrying?
You idiot. You really
think an excuse like that
is gonna play with Captain Levi?
Bad enough I had to
make your bed for you
this morning,
now you pull this crap?
Oh, shut it!
Who are you, my mom now?
We're back.
Wait, you were
chopping firewood?
Gotta stay in shape somehow.
You got grabbed by a Titan!
You should be in bed recovering!
Think you're wasting
your breath.
I caught her doing
sit-ups earlier, too.
Oh, so you're a nag and a spy!
What? How the hell...
Mikasa, you know you're
only human, right?
Funny. Almost feels
like we're back
in the Cadet Corps, doesn't it?
Mhmm.
Chaos. Makes you wonder
why they chose us
for this new Levi Squad.
Protecting Eren and Historia
is such an important mission.
Because we're all
so talented, I assume.
Sasha, what did you
just shove into your bag?
It's something that's
definitely not bread.
Really? What did I tell you?
C'mon, put it back.
Hey! Can we focus here?
We've gotta finish cleaning
before the captain gets back!
The bread, Sasha.
- Uuh...
- What's all the commotion?
- ..done this now?
- You know
we have to
conserve our rations!
You really think you can
just keep pullin' this crap!
Well I'm sick of...!
I am quite certain
I gave you enough time.
Never mind. We can discuss your
utter failure at a later date.
Eren.
Huh?
Hange is anxious to
get the experiment underway.
Right. Yes, sir.
Eren!
What's wrong, Eren? Get up!
The future of humanity
depends on you, damn it!
Get up!
Third time, and his
form's changed again.
He's not even ten meters tall,
and some of
his body lacks muscle.
Plus, Eren's scrawny
ass is hanging out.
I can see that!
Eren! Think you can still move?
Give us a signal
or something, will ya?
Eren!
Mikasa, wait up!
Great. The brat's at it again.
Off to the rescue.
She never learns, does she?
There's no response.
We're done here.
Eren!
Hot! Think you can ease up
on the steam a little?
Hey, be careful with him.
Can't you see he's bleeding?
You see his face, Moblit?
Sketch! Quick!
We gotta get this!
Section Commander!
Have you no compassion at all?
Ah!
Um. Sorry about that.
Not the outcome we'd hoped for.
We're still a long way
from being able
to use Eren's Titan
to seal the wall.
Yes. We've known
all along this would be
like grasping
at proverbial straws.
The plan's strategically sound.
And simple in theory.
All we need
is to get Eren there.
This could still work. But it's
going to depend on him.
Experiment's over.
All troops, withdraw at once!
Withdrawing! Go!
Make sure we weren't seen!
Right!
You ride back
to the house with Eren.
I'm going with Hange's group.
We're headed for Trost.
Sir.
You must
find her with all haste.
She is the key.
She may know things
we understand but poorly.
I see. Another failure, then.
Imagine if it had worked.
We could've plugged the hole in
Shiganshina in less than a day.
What we need is information.
It's not like there are
books on the subject.
That would make things too easy.
We do have Christa.
No. Historia Reiss.
Maybe she can
give us some insight
into the nature of the walls.
I did some digging
and found a report about
her life before the cadets.
The illegitimate daughter
of Lord Reiss.
Hers was not a happy childhood.
Lord Reiss is the key
to all this somehow.
Why would a mere regional lord
know the secrets of the walls?
Huh?
What are you doing?
You should still be in bed!
I'm all right.
I already slept a whole day.
Besides, it's my fault
the plan got shelved,
so the least I can do is help.
No! You tried, didn't you?
Don't beat yourself up.
All I care about
is getting a chance
to bring down the Beast Titan.
That hairy bastard
took everything from me.
I want it dead.
It's about time
to switch lookouts.
You ready?
Must be nice.
You and the others
know what you want,
even if it won't be easy to get.
But with Ymir gone,
I've lost my purpose.
I don't even know what
I'm fighting for anymore.
Saving her is
something to fight for.
Mm. Maybe.
At the time, I didn't
understand what she was doing.
I just wanted her to be safe.
Since then, I've been thinking.
When she left,
Ymir chose her own path.
I have no right to change that.
She doesn't need me to.
Finally. About time
you started talking again.
Hm?
When we got here,
you told us your story,
but then you just
kept your mouth shut.
Stopped smiling, too.
Why should I bother?
Huh?
Sorry, but the sweet little
Christa you thought you knew...
Well, that girl
isn't me anymore.
Good. I didn't really like her.
No one's actually as nice
as you pretended to be.
It was unnatural,
and, frankly, exhausting.
Oh.
Now. Well, now you're
just a normal girl.
Stupidly honest, maybe,
but still normal enough.
Still, you don't have to
decide about Ymir yet.
There's a part of me
that still thinks...
How did I forget that?
Hange and the others are back!
We're meeting in the main room.
Now, what's this about?
I'm sorry. Pastor Nick.
He was murdered.
Today. In the Trost barracks.
Hey!
Messing with
our crime scene, Scout?
Don't get any closer.
This isn't your jurisdiction.
A simple robbery murder.
There've been
a string of 'em lately.
I'm not buying it!
His nails were torn out...
Which unit are you in?
Section Commander Hange,
Fourth Squad.
And I'm XO Moblit Berner.
Heh. You know, when your
whole branch is garbage,
being high-ranked doesn't
make you smell any sweeter.
Listen. That man
wasn't killed by a titan.
One person killed another.
This isn't Scout business.
You're with
the First Interior Squad.
Funny. What're the capital's
MPs doing down here in Trost?
What's so strange about it?
Somebody has to get
the real work done
while you people
run around playing soldier.
Yes. You're completely right.
I see now I'm worthless
compared to you.
Simply being in
your presence is an honor.
Please, allow me
to shake your hand!
All right.
You said it was a robbery?
Poor Nick. I didn't realize
he even had anything
that was worth stealing.
Of course, he did.
Everybody knows the Church
makes all its
little trinkets out of iron.
Are you saying
Nick was affiliated with
the Order of the Walls?
What are you playing at?
He was a friend of mine,
that's why I rushed down here.
Except... I thought
he was a craftsman.
Making chairs or something.
I even put that on his
application to board here.
Let go!
Still. I suppose
this is a reminder
that we never really know people
as well as we think we do.
Enough. Let go!
Of course! Sorry.
Well, then, I wish you luck
with the investigation.
When you catch the culprit,
will you tell them
something for me?
"You may feel that what
you did to him was justified,
perhaps even righteous. Well,
I don't give a single shit
what your motivation was.
I promise you,
I will personally see to it
that you are tortured, and the
horrors visited upon you
will be greater than
any my friend suffered.
Yes. Far greater."
Please pass that along.
We'll leave you to it.
The pastor.
You think they killed him?
Yes, I do. That man's name
was Djel Sannes.
The skin on his fist
was split open.
Nick was tortured by
the Interior Military Police.
And then murdered.
I figured
the Church would want to
get their hands on Nick
when they learned
he was cooperating
with the Scouts.
That's why I hid his identity
and had him
stay in the barracks.
I never imagined they would
use soldiers to kill him.
This was my fault. I should
have been more careful.
They tortured him.
Presumably for information.
Did they just want to know
what he'd passed on to us?
Most likely.
But these are the Interior
MPs we're dealing with.
So you can bet there's
something deeper at work here.
Now, how many nails
was the good pastor missing?
Uh?
How many? You saw, right?
I only caught a glimpse of him,
but all the nail beds
I saw were empty.
People who talk, talk after one.
If they don't, ripping off more
won't make a difference.
I'm impressed. I didn't
think highly of Pastor Nick.
But whatever his faults,
he stuck by his beliefs
until the end.
Which means... they have no idea
we know about the Reiss family.
But, the government
is up to something.
And we've got
a target on our backs.
Captain Levi, sir.
I have a message
from Commander Erwin.
I went to tell him
about Pastor Nick,
but he gave me this
and sent me off.
Get your gear, now!
We're leaving.
Make it look like
we were never here.
That was close.
What if they had caught us?
Would they rip our nails off?
How did Commander Erwin
know they were headed here?
The government's passed
down some new orders.
There's been a freeze on all
Scout activity outside the wall.
We're to hand over
Eren and Historia.
Captain. I didn't
have time to tell you,
but some MPs
came for the Commander
right after I left him.
What? Like he's
some kind of criminal?
They're bringing this fight
out into the open.
No more working
from the shadows.
They're going to protect
the walls' secrets at any cost.
But why? And what exactly
are they after
Eren and Historia for?
They don't want them dead,
so what are they planning?
Who knows?
But they want these two,
and they're not
being subtle about it.
Which makes
lingering here dangerous.
We'll move Eren
and Historia to Trost.
We're taking them
to the same district
where Pastor Nick
was just murdered?
Heading toward the interior
would be worse.
With Trost in a panic,
it should be easy to slip in.
And if things do go all to hell,
we can use these in the city.
That's true.
We don't know the identity
of our enemy yet.
I have an idea of
how we can change that.
Hange, I'll need you to
lend me some of your squad.
No problem.
All right, I'm going
after Commander Erwin.
Moblit's with me. The rest
of you will go with Levi.
Roger!
Hange!
Here.
I remembered a conversation
between Ymir and Bertholdt.
I wrote it down for you.
It's all there.
Thank you. I'll take
a look at it later.
Hiyah!
Rather quick
on the move, aren't they?
Heh. The kid may be
small, but he's disciplined.
I'll give him that.
An acquaintance of yours?
An old one.
Try not to walk
clustered together.
We'll stand out.
Eren and Historia,
just act normal.
Why's the royal flag
hanging everywhere?
Today must be the anniversary
of the king's coronation.
Once a year they hand out
extra rations to celebrate it.
Oh.
May I have
your attention, please.
King Fritz has heard
of the hardships in Trost.
He is donating the
royal family's reserves.
Form a line.
There's plenty to go around.
Oh, thank goodness!
Long live King Fritz!
All that food and
he's just giving it away?
It's not as if he needs it all.
Easier to control people
when they're not starving.
Handing out those
rations depleted more than
60% of the reserves.
That's a steep cost just to
raise morale a bit,
Lord Reiss. Quite steep.
It was necessary.
We had to do something
to improve the public's
opinion of the royal family.
Now we just need the other
pieces of the puzzle.
And the sooner
we have them, the better.
The Military Police
failed us again?
I'll return at once.
We'll continue the hunt.
No, we'll soon
have what we need.
Things are in motion now.
Behind us! Look out!
Armi...
Uh, I mean,
Christa and Eren!
Those bastards are
running off with them!
Will it really work again?
With that horse face of his,
we look nothing alike.
Well, Jean. Good luck.
Yeah. So nice.
Let me hear
how much you like it.
Well? How's that?
Feels good, doesn't it?
Come on, I'm dying
to hear that sweet voice.
This is why I didn't
want to go through this shit
a second time.
Screw being his body double.
Just give me one
little moan, lovely.
You know you want to.
How's everything going inside?
If we wait very much longer,
they'll see through
Armin's disguise.
He's... getting pawed at.
I see.
How's your leg? Any better?
I can move well enough.
Now, then. Did you notice?
These kidnappers are
obviously rank amateurs.
Why wouldn't they use
professionals
for a job like this?
You can handle
the rest on your own.
I'm going to
make my way to Eren.
Come and meet up
with me when you're done
taking out the trash here.
Yes, sir.
There's one more
thing you should know.
Just in case.
Tell Armin and the others, too.
You're sure about this?
These are the two
we're lookin' for?
Yeah, they fit the descriptions
we were given to a tee.
Huh? Where's the guard?
What the hell?
Don't even think about moving.
Conny! Are these four
really all of them?
Yeah, that's all.
No one else in the area.
Move again and you won't like
where the next shot hits.
All right! First,
we get these guys secured.
Then, we meet up
with the captain.
What do you mean?
Those are his orders.
He left a message, too.
You there! Out of the way!
Captain.
Well?
The road's crowded,
but I've seen nothing unusual.
It's not far to
Commander Pyxis' from here,
so I think we're good, but how's
the body double mission?
A success.
You don't seem
very pleased about that.
I'm not.
Something's wrong.
Military Police
can't be behind this.
They're too careful of their
reputation to use amateurs.
This is more like...
They'd know the wagon
would be followed.
It's support team
wouldn't be far behind.
Captain.
Wagon's almost
on the move again.
Nifa, you've heard of
Kenny the Ripper?
That mass-murderer
in the capital?
The one who slit the throats
of over a hundred MPs?
Of course, but, I always thought
he was just an urban legend.
The stories are all true.
He's no legend.
Huh?
I lived with him.
Back when I was a kid.
Yeah. Very funny, sir.
This isn't really the time
to be making jokes.
That's right. He wouldn't
care about using amateurs.
The team would trail the
wagon from both rear angles.
They'd choose a spot high up.
Somewhere with
a clear line of sight.
Nifa!
Long time, Levi.
Still a runt,
or have you grown some?
Woo-hoo!
Nope. Don't look like you've
changed much at all, boy.
Kenny!